I want to begin with a simple truth.
Often in the workplace today,
we're doing a lot of communicating
and not a lot of connecting.
What are you saying when you're not speaking?
It's those moments in between
where so much of that dialogue is happening.
Because now leadership is more than the word
that just come out of our mouth.
It is about that connection.
And I wanna challenge you today to think about
how do you create that environment
where other people can show up smarter,
can show up more powerful,
can show up more productive.
That's what we're going to begin to dig into today.
My name is Stephen de Wit and I am a sexologist
and an expert in how humans connect.
We are facing an epidemic of disengagement
that drains performance
and that is driving your best people out the door.
I have sat down and worked with people
at the cutting edge of human behavior
when they're struggling with things
that maybe you haven't even thought about
in your professional life.
Because the future is getting faster,
but where you can differentiate yourself
is leading human.
How you listen to someone
directly impacts how they show up.
We put that pressure on ourselves
that we have to be these expert communicators
where I really want you to lean in
to be an expert connector.
The lead human model is built on one truth,
that performance follows connection.
When leaders develop their relational intelligence,
they learn how to read what's unspoken,
to be able to fix what's broken
and to be able to rebuild trust when that's been lost.
For when leaders choose to connect before they correct,
everything changes.
Trust deepens, engagement rises
and people feel safe to bring their bet.
Through the power of awareness and choice,
we can take that friction of leadership,
that silence, that tension,
that unsaid defensiveness,
we can make that into fuel for connection,
where fear becomes curiosity,
where defensiveness becomes dialogue,
where pressure becomes presence.
Because when we choose connection over control,
not only do we lead better,
but we build cultures people never want to lead.
Thank you for being in the room today with me
and doing the work.
I wish you all the best.